hey guys this looks like a fun one I'm
assuming it's a rectangle with a quarter
circle and a semicircle I'm thinking
it's safe to assume those things they
give us the width of the rectangle but
they do not give us the height if you
want to try it on your own pause it
right now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 first let's label the radius of the
semicircle R sub one and we'll label the
radius of the quarter Circle R sub 2 the
area of this semicircle is then going to
be pi r sub 1^ 2 / 2 and the area of
this quarter Circle would be PK R sub 2^
2 / 4 so to solve for the question mark
we're going to add these two areas
together so now let's play around with
this a little bit so we have the radius
right here let's put the radius again
right here so we can see that R2 is
equal to double of R1 so we can write an
expression to say that R2 is equal to
double R1 and let's substitute in the
place of this R2 let's make it to R1 and
let's do the same thing down here this
R2 will make it 2 R1 and now we don't
really need this anymore this Square
will go to both the 2 and the r sub one
so we can rewrite this 2 R sub 1^ 2 as
2^ 2 R sub 1^ 2 and 2^2 is equal to 4 at
this point we could just cancel out the
fours but I want to give it a common
denominator with this two so let's
simplify the 4 over 4 to be 2 over 2 and
let's rearrange these now we have piun R
sub 1^ 2 / 2 + 2 piun R sub1 2/ 2 after
we add these together we will have 3
piun R sub 1^ 2 / 2 and this looks
important let's put a box around it so
now all we got to do is find the length
of R sub one and I think I know how to
do that take each of these radi and
rotate them to right here and let's
complete this right triangle we already
know that the base is 4 cm and we also
know this is R sub one so we can do the
Pythagorean theorem we have R sub 1^ 2 +
4^2 is equal to well this would be 3 R
sub 1^ 2 well this 4 SAR would be equal
to 16 and this Square would go to both
the three and the r sub 1 so it become
3^ 2 R sub 1^ 2 and 3^2 is equal to 9
and then we can subtract R sub 1^ 2 from
both sides on the left hand side we just
have 16 and on the right hand side we'll
have 8 R sub 1^ 2 and then we can divide
both sides by 8 and that gives us 2 is
equal to R sub 1^ 2 and then we can
square root both sides and that gives us
R sub 1 is equal to theare < TK of 2 and
that is exactly what we needed to know
because now in the place of R sub one we
can plug in square < TK of two and then
the square root and the square can
cancel each other out and the two on top
and bottom can also cancel each other
out so the answer to our question is 3
pi and we give it a label of unit
squared that's the Blue Area how
exciting